Carey Orr Cartoons
Carey Orr Cartoons
- Cartoons
  - 1916-1928
    - Shoo!", 1923; 1923.0061. Orr; A stork labeled "The Balkans" carries a newborn baby, "Another War," in its beak. On the ground below mothers are scurrying away as they run to their homes overflowing with children. Those mothers are "Germany," "Turk," "Austria," "France," "England," and "Belgium."sketches for unknown drawings on verso. Words are listed down the right side for ideas. (Oversize 3)
    - The situation is growing more and more embarrassing., 1923; 1923.0062.Orr; "Mars" inside the building "The War Game" is saying goodbye to "Berlin Gov't" as he leaves walking down the sidewalk. "Berlin Gov't" is only wearing a barrel for clothing and it is labeled "Disintegration of Germany." Parts of the barrel are falling off and are labeled "Ruhr," "Bavaria," and "Saxony." In the distance is the "World" who looks on confused." (Oversize 3)
    - Stealing their stuff., 1923; 1923.0063.Orr; A man labeled "Napoleonic Imperialism," "Poincare," "Bismarckian Statecraft," and "Hohenzollern insolence" stands in front of a full length mirror admiring his military costume. A trunks behind him are labeled "Wilhelm II.," "Napoleon I.," and "Bismarck." In the background "The World" looks onto the scene and says "Wonder where he thinks he's goin'?"doodles to unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 3)
    - Still there are many people who would be willing to trade places., 1923; 1923.0064.Orr; A man, whose hat is labeled "The Croaker," sits on the ground labeled "America." He is holding a wreath and crying into his hand saying, "This country has gone to the dogs! Scandas - Graft - Taxes - Corruption! Everything's wrong!" In the distance is the "Immigration fence" that has a large lock on it. The distant commotion has clouds labeled: We Want In!", "Japanese Protest against exclusion!!", "Italian Protest!", "Greeks, - Russians - Serbians - Etc."sketches to unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 3)
    - Stopping War?, 1923; 1923.0065.Orr; The large barrel of a cannon labeled "War" is behind a bunker of "Greed, Ambition and Hatred." At the mouth of the barrel "Idealist" doves have built a nest of "Pacifism." The dove holds a twig of "Propaganda" in its beak and says "We'll plug it up."contains a preliminary sketch of a man is chopping down a tree labeled "Public Confidence" with an axe. Uncle Sam appears in the background with a rifle." (Oversize 3)
    - A sudden affection., 1923; 1923.0066.Orr; A woman labeled "Congress" is standing outside the capitol building bandaged and crying into her apron. Bricks labeled "Blame," "Criticism of Congress by LaFollette" are strewn beneath her feet. Outside a picket fence stand two men. One is labeled "Voter" and the other is labeled "LAF" who carries a large bouquet of flowers labeled "Power to override Supreme Court. "Laf" says to the "Voter," "I wish you'd deliver this to her for me." Congress" says, "I've lived with 'Bob' for twenty years, and that's the first kindness he has ever shown me."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 3)
    - Suggestion for a new windshield design., 1923; 1923.0067.Orr; A man labeled "Careless Driver" is behind the steering wheel of an auto labeled "Criminal prosecution for killing pedestrians." In a bubble to the left the driver envisions himself behind bars labeled "Penitentiary sentence."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 3)
    - A suggestion for the "Party" toast.", 1923; 1923.0068.Orr; A "Farmer" leans over a cup of milk and milk jug labeled "14 cents." The "laborer" raises his cup of "14% cider" to toast him saying "Well, brother! Here's to th' lil' ole 'Farmer-labor Party.'" A newspaper in the foreground has the headlines: Prohibition commissioner Haynes 'to interfere as little as possible' with the right of the farmer to make cider." A cat in the background is growling over spilt milk." (Oversize 4)
    - A suggestion to France., 1923; 1923.0069.Orr; Cartoon in two panels: 1. A dog, "French Militarism," is chasing a rabbit, "Germany," into a hollowed out log labeled, "Bolshevism." The text that accompanies it reads, "Better call off your dog - " 2. A large bear emerges from the log now labeled, "War with Russia."French militarism" is running away with his tail between his legs. The caption reads "...before he brings something home with him." (Oversize 4)
    - Sunk so low., 1923; 1923.0070.Orr; A man sits on "Russia" on the globe. His clothes are torn and he has a disheveled appearance. He grits his teeth and shakes his fist to the sky that is filled with light labeled "Christianity." His other hand holds a piece of paper that says "Soviet Denunciation of religion." Empty liquor bottles are near him."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Tax exempt., 1923; 1923.0071.Orr; U.S. Taxpayer" stands at the window of the "Revenue Collector." The "Fourth installment - Income Tax" is due and the "Taxpayer" has one hand in his pocket as he glances up to a picture on the wall next to him. The picture has a large man labeled "Europe" sitting in a chair with "Plans for future wars." Next to him is a waste can filled with "Unpaid debts to U.S."sketches of unknown drawings on verso. The numbers 645 in a circle appear on the recto lower right edge. (Oversize 4)
    - Tickle! Tickle!, 1923; 1923.0072.Orr; A farmer, who seems quite content and smiling with his arms crossed, leans against a fence labeled "Farmer's Grouch." Behind the fence is the apparition of a woman in a bonnet with a scarf labeled "Law of supply and Demand." She holds a shaft of wheat and is tickling the farmer's ear. " (Oversize 4)
    - Too weak to swing it., 1923; 1923.0073.Orr; J.B." is handing "Egypt" an "Ultimatum. In the foreground is "The League," whose stature is very diminutive, trying to pick up an enormous bat labeled "Powers conferred upon the league."to unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Trying to start a dog fight?, 1923; 1923.0074.Orr; An "American Merchant" carries a package in his hand as he walk s down the sidewalk with his large bulldog labeled "American Boycott on Japanese Goods." Coming around the corner is a small dog barking labeled "Japanese boycott on U.S. Goods." A Japanese man labeled "Jap Alarmist" is yelling to the dog "Sic 'em! Sic 'em!""doodles" for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 4)
    - The unanswered challenge another argument for a state constabulary., 1923; 1923.0075.Orr; A cowboy labeled "Bloody Williamson County" has ammunition hanging around his neck, a rope and bloody knife in one hand and his other bloody hand is shooting off a gun whose smoke cloud is labeled "Law Defiance." He is walking out of a cemetery whose tomb stones are labeled: Herrin Murders,"Herrin killed," and "Murder." In the background is the apparition of a "State Policeman" mounted on horseback ready to strike the cowboy.""doodles" for cartoon on verso. Williamson County in Southern Illinois is known as "Bloody Williamson" after the "Herrin Massacre" which resulted from a confrontation between unionized mine workers that attacked the mine of William Lester who continued to mine during the strike. The strike breakers were taken as prisoners and eventually murdered. The sheriff was absent during these events and the coroner ruled the killings by "unknown individuals" and caused by actions of Southern Illinois Coal Company and not the striking miners. Over 20 strike breakers were buried in a common grave in Herrin Cemetery." (Oversize 4)
    - Two viewpoints., 1923; 1923.0076.Orr; American Labor" is walking up the steep path of a mountain labeled "Living Standards." Behind him is "Sane citizen," who says, "Look how high up we are!" as he points down the mountain to the "Struggling masses of Europe." Walking in front of "American Labor" is "Professional Malcontent" who says, "Look how low down we are!" as he points up the mountain where a sign is labeled "Utopia."on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - The warlike record of a peaceful man., 1923; 1923.0077.Orr; Uncle Sam is smoking a pipe and scratching his head and ruminates as he reads a large sign: American Wars - Revolutionary War. - War of 1812. - War with Mexico. - War of Rebellion. - Spanish-American War. Mexican Hostilities. - The World War. - The Next War." Uncle Sam says, "As I look back over my record, I remember that I thought each war would be my last - I never got ready for the next one - Maybe if I'd expect war and prepare for it, I'd get in less trouble - certainly not more!" (Oversize 4)
    - Warren Gamaliel Harding, 1865-1923.", 1923.0078.Orr; A portrait of Harding is draped with the American Flag. Uncle Sam stands next to a table glancing up at the portrait. On the desk are scrolls labeled "Prosperity,"Reconstruction of America,"Peace Efforts," and "Four Power Treaty." A wreath labeled "America's Affection," sits in an empty chair."died on August 2, 1923 of a heart attack in San Francisco. Harding and his wife had traveled cross-country to visit Alaska and to meet the public prior to the 1924 elections." (Oversize 4)
    - Watch your clothes, Warren!", 1923; 1923.0079.Orr; Warren G. Harding is in a bathing suit and ready to dive off a diving board into a muddy pond labeled "World Court." His clothes are on the side of the water bank. Hiding behind a tree and eyeing Harding's clothes is "Hi Johnson." The clothes are labeled "G. O. P. Nomination 1924.""doodles" to unknown drawings on verso. Harding died of a heart attack on August 2, 1923." (Oversize 4)
    - Watch your step!, 1923; 1923.0080.Orr; Uncle Sam stands on the globe with his feet dug into the earth. Behind him is a small man "Pro-Leaguer" that is pushing him towards the words "World Court" that are formed out of rope and labeled "Foreign intrigue," and "Entanglement in European quarrels.""doodles" for cartoon on verso." (Oversize 4)
    - Where the trail leads., 1923; 1923.0081.Orr; A large elephant labeled "G.O.P." with two men riding on back is headed for "World Court" which is a narrow ledge at the top of a cliff. The elephant is starting to rear not wanting to fall off the cliff. The cliff is labeled "Party Split." In back of the elephant and twisting the elephant tail is a man labeled "Pro-European pressure." In the background can be seen the Capitol dome. "sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - White Caps, 1923; 1923.0082.Orr; Gov. Walton" is riding in a small canoe labeled "The Governorship." The turbulent water labeled "Oklahoma Politics" is filled with white caps labeled "K.K.K." in the background. " (Oversize 4)
    - Withholding the feed till she produces the milk., 1923; 1923.0083.Orr; A farmer labeled "Poincare" is frantically milking an emaciated cow labeled "Germany." Scattered on the ground are empty buckets labeled "Reparations." Straw in the foreground is labeled "The Ruhr," and "German Industries."to unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Wonder if he will pass it around?", 1923; 1923.0084.Orr; At the "Germany General Store" a man behind the counter weighs "Reparations Candy" on the "Dawes Plan" scale. A young boy, "France," stands at the glass counter and turns to two young pretty girls behind him. The first girl, "French Debt to U.S.," says ,"Hello, Jacques." The next girl, "French debt to England," says "Lo!"drawings for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Wonder if they really have the patients interest at heart?, 1923; 1923.0085.Orr; Ailing Farmer" sits in a chair as he is surrounded by doctors labeled "Radical,"Political Quack," and "Old Doc Demagogue." They are saying, "An operation is essential," We must operate!" and "Yes! We must operate!" as they examine the "Farmer." The doctor's bag labeled "Anything to get votes" is in the foreground and has saws, hammers and various tools spilling out on the floor labeled "Nut legislation,"and "Crazy Schemes."sketches to unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Wonder what the neighbors who furnished so much advice awhile back are thinking now?, 1923; 1923.0086.Orr; Sec. Mellon" is using a large pruner, "Harding Administration" to prune a tree labeled "Gov't Financing." Limbs labeled "Tax cut,"Sur tax cut" and "Excess profits tax removal" are lying on the ground. Behind a fence are "Farm Block,"Lafollette," and "Radicals" yelling, "He's Ruining it!" and "Stop." The bottom right corner shows a tree lush with foliage and fruit labeled "$125,000,000.00 Surplus," and "National debt reduction $1,6000,000,000.00." The people behind the fence now look up at the tree perplexed."of elephants and donkey to unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - The work of Little Joe Worry., 1923; 1923.0087.Orr; Cartoon in six panels: 1. One man says to another, "I just got a wonderful tip on the stock market - Buy Copper Consolidated" It's goin' way up!" The other man says, "Sure, Alec, Go ahead an' gamble - I promise to come an' visit you at the poor house! Heh-heh. 2. A little man that had been peering from around the corner says to the second man, "It's all right to be cautious, but if you ever happen to hit the stock market right you're fixed for life." He replies, "Maybe I'd better look into that stock that Alec recommended. 3. He goes to a stock broker and says, "I'd like to see some of your 'Copper Consolidated' Stock." The little man says, "Why don't you take a little flier? Nothing venture, nothing gain." 4. The little man says, "I'll bet Alec bought more of that stock than you did - he'll be a rich man some day!" The man walks away saying "Dog gone! I wish I had more money to invest in it!" 5. The man says to Alec, "Well, Alec, did you get that 'Copper consolidated?" Alec replies, "Nope! Your hunch was right!" 6. Alec continues, "I just found out the stock is no good!!" The little man writes on a pad of paper "Victim no. 8784..612....." (Oversize 4)
    - The wrong target., 1923; 1923.0088.Orr; A large bear, "Crime Menace," has climbed on a weak tree sapling that is bending. At the edge of the sapling is a man labeled "Public" that is holding on the trunk for dear life. Below them are hunters firing their rifles at "Public." The hunters are labeled "Sympathy for criminal, "Incompetent judge,"Abuse of pardon power," and Crook Lawyer," who says, "Don't let him hurt the poor beast."of preliminary sketch for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Why waste money on him? All he does is to save the country in the time of war., 1923; 1923.0089.Orr; A small man in a tattered U.S. naval uniform is standing on the street corner begging with his hat labeled "Navy appropriations." A large man labeled "Congress" hoovers over him holding in his arms a large scroll labeled "Vote getting appropriations."Congress" says to the small sailor, "Appropriations? What for?? How many votes can you deliver?"on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - You'd think after a few such occurrences, they'd make up and be friends.", 1923; 1923.0090.Orr; Cartoon in six scenes: 1. A woman brings a large bowl labeled "Prosperity" as she calls for her dog, Towser, and cat, Tabby. 2. Towser is labeled "Advancing prices," and Tabby is labeled "Advancing wages" and both are approaching the "Prosperity." 3. They both being to growl at one another. 4. They begin to fight and there is "price jump" and "Wage jump." 5. The fighting is a whirl of "Strikes," and "Lockouts." 6. Towser and Tabby both sit by the broken "Prosperity" in exhaustion with their tongues hanging out and labeled "Price Depression," and "Wage Depression."sketches to wagon being pulled by horses for unknown drawing. (Oversize 4)
    - untitled, 1924; 1924.0001.Orr; Apparitions of Wilson and Lodge are seen in the background with U.S. troops saluting them as they embrace. On a rocky shore, waves a breaking against "Earthly Struggles." Two tombstones are on the shore with a flag at half-mast. The tombstones read: Woodrow Wilson - Our war President - proposed league of nations," and "Henry Cabot Lodge - U.S. Senator - Led opposition to League."sketch for cartoon on verso. On lower left corner of verso is "1924 - Death of Woodrow Wilson and Henry Cabot Lodge" written in pencil." (Oversize 4)
    - The Democratic Program., 1924; 1924.0002.Orr; Cartoon in four panels: 1. A man, "West" sits in front of his radio that is blasting, "Radical appeal to farms by Charlie Bryan." 2. A man, "East," is by his radio that is blasting, "Conservative appeal to big business by Davis." The caption, "If they don't get tuned in wrong," is for the last two panels. 3. "West" is furious when he hears, "Conservative appeal to big business by Davis," coming from his radio. 4. "East" stands growling in front of his radio as he hears, "Radical appeal to farmers by Charlie Bryan."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - The driver quits., 1924; 1924.0003.Orr; A car labeled "The Radical Movement" with a "Red" flag waving from it is speeding down a road. "LaFollette" jumps out from the drivers seat saying "It's gotten beyond my control." The steering wheel is labeled "Leadership." In the backseat of the vehicle are "Ladd,"Brookhart," and Shipstead" who are wondering what is going on."sketches (including a train) for cartoon on verso. Brookhart, Smith W. (1869-1944) advocated government ownership of railroads. He eventually shared the populist belief that big business and the monetary policies of the federal government threatened to deny freedom and opportunities to farmers and small business owners. Shipstead, Henrik. (1881-1960) was elected as a Farm-Laborite to the U.S. Senate. " (Oversize 4)
    - The elephant hunter., 1924; 1924.0004.Orr; A man labeled "Democrats" is caught between the wires of a barbed wire fence as he tries to climb between it. He has four rifles he is carrying that start firing. The rifles are labeled: Klan Issue,"League Issue,"Wet & Dry Issue," and "Radical & Conservative Issues." In the far distance is the outline of a smiling elephant."sketches for unknown drawing on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Even Uncle Hiram wouldn't be able to escape the ultimate effects of the general fall., 1924; 1924.0005.Orr; Davis" turns to a "Farmer" saying "Look what I'm doing for you," as he pushes over a huge circle of dominos. The dominos read: Davis' Low Tariff Plank - to enable the farmer to buy cheaper,"Flood of cheap foreign goods into U.S."Less demand for American made articles, "U.S. Business depression, "Bankruptcies, " Discharge of Employees - Lowered wages"Nationwide unemployment."General privation and poverty,"Less demand for everything, including foodstuffs," and "Fall in prices of Farm products." The final domino when it would fall would crush the "Farmer" standing in front of it." (Oversize 4)
    - Fed up., 1924; 1924.0006.Orr; A man labeled "Public" is sitting at a dining table labeled "Hotel politics" and "G.O.P. convention."Public" is stuffed and his buttons are popping from his vest. He puts his hands up gesturing to the waiter to stop bringing food and says "Have a heart, bob!" The waiter, labeled "LaFollette," is bringing in a large tray of dishes labeled "Progressive Con.,"More bunk," and Politics."for unknown drawings on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Fertile soil., 1924; 1924.0007.Orr; In a distant field is the "Democrats vs. Republicans Mud Throwing Contest." Men are covered in mud and flinging it at one another. Rushing to the scene is "LaFollette" pushing a large wheelbarrow filled with "Seeds of Radicalism,"Pink Propaganda," and "Seeds of Dissatisfaction." (Oversize 4)
    - Fighting for the farmer., 1924; 1924.0008.Orr; LaFollette" and "Chas. Bryan" are racing with "Gold Bricks" and "Farm Promises" to a farmer and both exclaiming, "I saw him first!" The farmer in the distance is labeled "Farmer Vote" and he stands behind his fence scratching his head."on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Fighting for her affections., 1924; 1924.0009.Orr; Two men, both labeled "Political Faction," are in a "Congress Tax Fight." As they roll on the floor and beat one another up they cause an "Economic Disturbance" and break the furnishings within the room. A beautiful woman, "Public Opinion" stands looking disgusted at the scene with her "Ballot" in her hand as she prepares to leave the room." (Oversize 4)
    - Germany - "Peace is H----", 1924; 1924.0010.Orr; A man in a military uniform and labeled "France" sits on a man's stomach. Lying beside this man is a sign that says "The Ruhr - The heart of German industry." He is carrying an empty basket labeled "German reparations payments."France" says to this man, "I'll sit right here until you gather 'em!" as he points to a distance tree in the background. The tree has bags of money hanging from it's branches and is labeled "Reparations demands."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Getting ready for the big scene., 1924; 1924.0011.Orr; Eliza G.O.P.," an elephant, carries her small baby labeled "Her Record." She stands next to a man labeled "Dem. Party" who holds his whip of "Criticism" and says, "Wait till I get my bloodhounds!"Dem. Party" stands next to a dog house filled with dogs, "Dem Pledges." A flag waves from the house labeled "N.Y. Convention." In the foreground is a river filled with stones labeled: Limited immigration,"World court," Tax reduction,"Merchant marine,"Republic Pledges, "No debt cancellation,"Retention of Philippines,'"Protective tariff, " and "Naval preparedness'" with a sign labeled "To Election." On the shore a movie director labeled "Voter" stands behind his camera labeled "Ballot Box" ready to capture the scene of crossing the water."sketches for cartoon on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - Go slow and keep to the road., 1924; 1924.0012.Orr; A vehicle labeled "U.S.A." is going through a ticker tape parade labeled "European Propaganda." Pieces of paper falling are labeled: Russian propaganda, " French propaganda,"English propaganda,"League Propaganda,"German Propaganda,"French Propaganda,"World Court propaganda" and "Belgium Propaganda." A sign points the way for "American Interests."title was paper clipped to the top of the cartoon. (Oversize 4)
    - Going to cut everything down but the farmer?, 1924; 1924.0013.Orr; Sitting in a tree of "U.S. Industries" is a "Farmer" on the "Farm Prices" branch. Other branches are "business," and "Labor." Half way up the tree, with a saw in his hand and cutting down the branch the"Farmer" is on is "Bryan" saying, "Now don't you worry! We're going to leave you up here!" At the base of the tree is "Davis" with a large axe labeled "Low Tariff" who is in the process of cutting the entire tree down."on verso. (Oversize 4)
    - About all that family has done since moving into the neighborhood is to make trouble for everybody., 1924; 1924.0014.Orr; A house labeled "The seasons of 1924" has two people labeled "Crazy spring & summer" hanging out the top window. "Short Fall" is seen entering the house. On a snow bank outside the house is "Winter" who is throwing a large snowball at a man who says, "He's just like the rest of the crazy outfit!"right corner has the following glued to the surface: Reg. U.S. Pat Off.: Copyright 1924 by the Chicago Tribune. (Oversize 4)
    - After six years - getting tired of waiting to be saved., 1924; 1924.0015.Orr; A man is lying on a beach under a large beach umbrella labeled "Rich Uncle Sam." In the waters of "Financial troubles" is a woman, "Europe," who says, "If he doesn't come out and rescue me pretty soon, I'm going ashore."Europe is standing in knee deep water and holding a lifesaver that is labeled "Dawes' Plan."the verso: Along time ago Wm. Rich got up the idea of train a horse to ride."Darn th' rich!" Top part of the title is cut off. Pin hole in upper right corner." (Oversize 4)